In this video, I'm going to give you
some guidance on completing your unit
three spreadsheet software assessment.
So at this point you should have
now completed unit one and unit two,
and you've moved on to unit three.
As with the other two units, you
work through each of the sessions
and you will be able to complete
relevant sections of the assessment
as you work through those sessions.
So I'm just going to bring up
the actual assessment document.
So I'll navigate to the folder
containing that, double-click, that
will open it up in Word And it's
exactly the same format as the word
processing and presentation documents.
And I can then scroll down.
I can see the learning outcomes
for spreadsheet software, and also
Improving Productivity Using IT.
And again, there is another scenario.
So read through this scenario,
make sure that you fully understand
what the task is asking you to do.
And then you can move on to
the actual sections, completing
the actual assessment.
So exactly the same as word processing
and presentations, you need to
provide a screenshot showing the
location of the saved assessment.
So that would be that folder there.
Take a screenshot and paste it into there.
Then there are some questions
and then you come on to actually
creating the spreadsheet.
So you've been provided with
the content for the spreadsheet.
You just then need to insert that
into the actual blank spreadsheet
that you've opened and work through
each of the tasks within there.
You will be asked to add certain
screenshots at various locations,
but again, it will make it clear.
So that will be the spreadsheet that
you've created at various points.
So once you've done that as with
word processing, I always recommend
actually once I've completed
it, highlighting it in green.
And then as I work through, I can
see exactly what has been done.
If there's anything I'm unsure of
I would highlight it in yellow.
Once you've completed part
two, you can then go on to part
three and you are provided with
another spreadsheet to analyze.
So you don't need to submit this actual
and fruit and veggie data when you've
finished your assessment, but it is
required to assist you in answering
the questions in this part here.
You would then move on to part
four, which is about formatting
and presenting your data.
It asks you to apply various formatting
and make changes to the spreadsheet.
An important point to note as at
step 12, you need to print your
sales data worksheet as a PDF file.
If you're using a Windows based machine,
you can select Microsoft print to PDF.
However, if you are using a Mac you can't
do that you need to select save as PDF.
So it's very similar, but you just don't
have the Microsoft print to PDF feature.
You need to save it as a PDF.
And this print out will be submitted to
your tutor for assessment, along with the
spreadsheet and the assessment document.
So again, once you've finished that
section, you will move on to part five,
which is about applying charts and graphs.
So again, follow all of the
instructions on there, apply the
screen prints where required.
And then in section six, it
is about quality control.
This section here is all about questions
and in part seven, it's all about
improving productivity and efficiency, and
it asks you to answer further questions.
Again, once you've completed, make sure
that you've happy with the work that
you've done checked through your work,
and then you will submit the assessment,
the PDF file and the file that you've
saved at "SS2 sales spreadsheet final".